Rajavel Pachamuthu

Network Consultant

♥ Kolding, Denmark

**** +45 55206486

☑ raj@rajavel.me

rajavel.me

Summary

Network Engineer with 15 years of experience in designing and deploying Network infrastructure for various Professional services companies and Telecom Service Providers. Proficient in delivering technical support and maintaining enterprise-wide area networks across multi-platform.

Skills

Prisma SD-WAN and Prisma Access, VeloCloud SD-WAN, Versa SD-WAN | VXLAN EVPN, NDFC | AWS and Azure Networking | Cisco switches & Routers | TCP/IP, BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, vPC, STP, VTP, EtherChannel | GRE, IPsec, DMVPN, MPLS, QoS, HSRP, VRRP, NAT | Cisco ISE, Cisco Prime, SolarWinds | Ansible.

Certifications

- CCNP-Enterprise Cisco Certified Network Professional Enterprise.
 - o Specialist: Enterprise Core, Enterprise Design, Enterprise advanced Infrastructure Implementation.
- AWS Certified Advanced Networking Specialty.
- Versa Certified SD-WAN Associate

Work Experience

HCL Technologies ApS, Denmark

June 2023 - Present

Network Consultant

- Project planning and development as well as implementation and commissioning of customised solutions in the field of enterprise networking and data center networking.
- Project implementation, commissioning, support and further development of already implemented solutions.

Tata Communications, Chennai, India

October 2020 - June 2023

Manager - SDWAN Engineering

- Designed and implemented Versa SD-WAN solutions for dedicated and multi-tenant deployments.
- Validated solution requirements from customers and create SOP documents for support teams.
- Analyzed customer solicitations (RFIs, RFPs, etc.), requirements and designed solution proposals.

Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India

July 2013 - October 2020

Network Specialist

- Installed & supported network infrastructure of a Danish Manufacturing company of 200+ locations.
- Migrated 200+ branch locations from traditional MPLS and DMVPN to VeloCloud SDWAN.
- Designed Cloud readiness project and enabled Network connectivity to Azure from Hubs and branches.

Sify Technologies Ltd, Chennai, India

November 2011 - July 2013

Global NOC Engineer

- Provisioned and supported MPLS VPN and Internet WAN circuits for customers.
- Integrated 100+ member bank branches under state owned IDRBT MPLS VPN network.
- Provided technical solutions and implemented new requirements for Managed Customers.

Firstsource Solutions, Chennai, India Junior NOC Engineer

September 2010 - November 2011

Allnet Systems Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, India

July 2009 - September 2010

Network Engineer

Education

Anna University, Chennai, India Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics & Communication Engineering)